# Jing Mai

Science Building #5, Peking University, No.5 Yiheyuan Road, Haidian District, Beijing 1000871 jingmai@pku.edu.cn \( \phi \) magic3007.github.io

# Bio

I am a second-year Ph.D. student in the Department of Computer Science at Peking University associated with the Center for Energy-Efficient Computing and Applications (CECA). I am a member of the *PKU-IDEA Lab*, advised by *Prof. Yibo Lin*. Previously, I received the B.S. degree in Computer Science and Technology from Peking University in 2021. My research focuses are machine learning-assisted EDA; my broader interests include MLSys, concurrency and probabilistic modeling.

## Education

#### Ph.D. in Computer Science

Sept. 2021 - Present

Center for Energy-efficient Computing and Applications (CECA), Peking University

Beijing, China

Advisor: Prof. Yibo Lin

#### B.S. in Computer Science and Technology

Sept. 2017 - June 2021

School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science (EECS), Peking University

Beijing, China

### **Publications**

(\* denotes alphabetical ordering or equal contribution)

#### Refereed Conference Papers .....

[C1] Jiarui Wang, **Jing Mai**, Zhixiong Di, Yibo Lin. A Robust FPGA Router with Concurrent Intra-CLB Rerouting. 28th Asia and South Pacific Design Automation Conference (**ASP-DAC**), 2023.

[C2] Yifan Chen, **Jing Mai**, Xiaohan Gao, Muhan Zhang, Yibo Lin. MacroRank: Ranking Macro Placement Solutions Leveraging Translation Equivariancy. 28th Asia and South Pacific Design Automation Conference (**ASP-DAC**), 2023.

[C3] **Jing Mai**, Yibai Meng, Zhixiong Di, Yibo Lin. Multi-Electrostatic FPGA Placement Considering SLICEL-SLICEM Heterogeneity and Clock Feasibility. 59th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (**DAC**), 2022.

[C4] **Jing Mai**\*, Zizheng Guo\*, Yibo Lin. Ultrafast CPU/GPU Kernels for Density Accumulation in Placement. 58th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (**DAC**), 2021.

## Journal Papers .....

[J1] Yihua Cheng, Zejia Fan, **Jing Mai**, Yifan Wu, Pengcheng Xu, Yuxuan Yan, Zhenxin Fu, Yun Liang. *Critique of "Planetary Normal Mode Computation: Parallel Algorithms, Performance, and Reproducibility" by SCC Team From Peking University. IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems(IEEE Trans Parallel Distrib Syst), 2021.* 

# Book Chapters .....

[B1] Yibo Lin, Zizheng Guo and **Jing Mai**. Deep Learning Framework for Placement, Machine Learning Applications in Electronic Design Automation, Springer, 2023, edited by Haoxing Ren and Jiang Hu. (**Invited Book Chapter**)

# **Research Experiences**

#### Shenzhen Giga Design Automation

Oct 2022 - Feb 2023

Software Development Intern

Beijing, China

Topics: Incremental Placement for Layout-driven Synthesis

#### Nanjing Industrial Innovation Center of EDA (NiCEDA)

Aug 2021 - Sept 2021

Software Development Intern

Shanghai, China

Topics: Dataflow-driven global placement

#### Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK)

July 2020 - Aug 2020

Summer Intern, co-advised by Prof. Yibo Lin and Prof. Bei Yu Topics: Electrostatics-Based global placement for FPGAs Shenzhen, China

# **Honors and Awards**

<ul> <li>The 3rd EDA Elite Challenge (Second Prize)</li> </ul>	Dec 2021
<ul> <li>Honors for Outstanding Undergraduate Graduates in Beijing (top 1%)</li> </ul>	May 2021
Beijing Challenge Cup Competition (Second Prize)	May 2021
Xiaomi Scholarship, Peking University	Dec 2020
<ul> <li>Honors for Merit Student, Peking University (top 5%)</li> </ul>	Dec 2019, Dec 2020
<ul> <li>Huawei Scholarship, Peking University</li> </ul>	Dec 2019
<ul> <li>Honors for Outstanding Academic Performance, Peking University</li> </ul>	Dec 2018
The 43rd ACM-ICPC Asia Regional Competition (Gold Award)	Nov 2018

# **Teaching and Mentoring Experience**

• **Teaching Assistant** – Optimization and Machine Learning in VLSI Design Automation, Peking University

2022

# **Skills**

#### **Programming Languages and Softwares**

C/C++, Python, Java, Pytorch, Tensorflow, MTpX, Git, CUDA, Docker, Data Analysis/Visualization(Pandas)

### Web Development

HTML5, JavaScript

#### **EDA Tools**

Xilinx Vivado

#### Languages

Mandarin, Cantonese, English, Japanese